<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LongYC</title>
    <description>Personal website of a software developer from Malaysia who likes technology, Node.js, Android, books, games, and teh tarik.
</description>
    <link>http://longyc.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://longyc.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 17:20:18 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 17:20:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Malaysia Fan Run 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run finisher medals since year 2014.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/07/2016-07-17-tm-fan-run-medals-since-2014.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started two years ago, first 10 KM run at &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/team-malaysia-fan-run-2014/&quot; title=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014.&quot;&gt;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014&lt;/a&gt;
and then 15 KM at &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/team-malaysia-fan-run-2015/&quot; title=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2015.&quot;&gt;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2015&lt;/a&gt;.
This year, joining for the third time,
I went for 21 KM half marathon which seems to be a first for TM Fan Run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-are-getting-better&quot;&gt;Things Are Getting Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event went quite well, the flag off time was 6 AM, one hour earlier compared to last year
so those who could not run fast (like me) can take less heat from the morning sun.
Also, the ribbon bar of the finisher medal is reverted back to the red-white-blue stripes
which I find way better than the one with TM logo used last year.
While most organisers will provide singlets instead of runners-T for half marathons,
it is not the case with TM Fan Run;
not that I have any problem with that because I have always liked the design
and this year’s got Olympic rings on it.
Besides, runners can wear the attire they prefer anyway -
there were quite a number of runners in Baju Melayu, it’s the month of Hari Raya Puasa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2016.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/07/2016-07-17-tm-fan-run.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-team-malaysia&quot;&gt;Go Team Malaysia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two years of TM Fan Run I joined, the theme had always been showing support to
Malayisan athletes participating in major sport events;
it was for Incheon Asian Games for 2014 and SEA Games for 2015.
This year’s race was no exception and in fact,
this year’s game is none other than the Rio 2016 Olympic Games.
So, may our Malaysian athletes able to perform at their peaks on the world stage, go Team Malaysia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run Runners-T 2014 to 2016.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/07/2016-07-17-tm-fan-run-shirts.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2016/07/team-malaysia-fan-run-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2016/07/team-malaysia-fan-run-2016/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur 2016.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/04/2016-04-26-aws-summit-kl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services has been around for years. Unfortunately for me,
I did not pay much attention due to the lack of a good use case.
However, things started to get interesting
when I get to use some of their services actively in work recently,
which is also why I attended AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur
held at One World Hotel in Selangor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;official-presence-in-malaysia&quot;&gt;Official Presence in Malaysia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur 2016 Opening Keynote.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/04/2016-04-26-aws-summit-kl-dr-vogels.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening keynote was delivered by none other than the Chief Technology Officer
of Amazon.com - Dr. Werner Vogels. The speech was great,
he explained how cloud computing can help scale businesses across a variety of industries.
Also, there was one much anticipated announcement
- AWS now has official presence in Malaysia;
probably a good boost of confidence in the cloud platform for potential adopters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multiple-tracks&quot;&gt;Multiple Tracks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur 2016 Developer Session.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/04/2016-04-26-aws-summit-kl-developer-session.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s Summit consists of multiple tracks
dedicated to different groups of audience.
Sadly though, the developer session that I’m interested in
gets a small hall which could only fit approximately 100 persons.
Mind you, there were about 2000 attendees and this hall was the only one
with people queuing outside waiting for their turn to get in.
The first session that I managed to get in was Twitch-Ready 3D-games development
with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lumberyard/&quot; title=&quot;Amazon Lumberyard&quot;&gt;Amazon Lumberyard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/gamelift/&quot; title=&quot;Amazon GameLift&quot;&gt;GameLift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
by Olivier Klein. The duo were launched earlier this year - Lumberyard
is a free, cross-platform game engine with an emphasize on Twitch integration
while GameLift is a service focused on scaling multiplayer games in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other developer sessions I got in were JavaScript &amp;amp; Node.js developmnet on AWS
(&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaScriptSDK/guide/&quot; title=&quot;AWS SDK for JavaScript&quot;&gt;AWS SDK for JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;)
and agile deployment using Git &amp;amp;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/&quot; title=&quot;AWS Elastic Beanstalk&quot;&gt;AWS Elastic Beanstalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,
both by Alex Smith. He showcased how the JS SDK can do just as much as
its counterpart in other languages and how to implement
&lt;a href=&quot;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/BlueGreenDeployment.html&quot; title=&quot;BlueGreenDeployment&quot;&gt;blue-green deployment&lt;/a&gt;
with Elastic Beanstalk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between those, I joined track 3 - a talk on
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&quot; title=&quot;AWS Lambda&quot;&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Markku Lepisto,
there was an showcase of implementing real time monitoring
on tweets mentioning &lt;em&gt;“Bieber”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;“Miley”&lt;/em&gt;, laughters assured.
In case anyone is not aware, AWS Lambda is a service for serverless computing
- essentially you push your code and it is ready to be executed
(think PHP sans the language and the need to manage any server,
 thus the term &lt;em&gt;serverless&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing-with-prizes&quot;&gt;Closing with Prizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;AWS Summit Kuala Lumpur 2016 Closing.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/04/2016-04-26-aws-summit-kl-closing.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing was accompanied by lucky draws which many were waiting for,
there were prizes like iPad Pro, Amazon Fire HD and even drones
if I remembered correctly. All in all, the event was good,
the talks given were, pun intended, AWSome.
The developer session needs a little bit more love though.
I’ll be looking forward a better organized Summit next year with
Amazon’s official presence in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2016/04/aws-summit-kl-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2016/04/aws-summit-kl-2016/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medium Is Blocked in Malaysia</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Medium is blocked in Malaysia.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2016/01/2016-01-31-unblock-medium.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawn from personal observation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot; title=&quot;Medium&quot;&gt;Medium (medium.com)&lt;/a&gt;
is probably not as popular in Malaysia when compared to other more established blog publishing platforms
like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.com/&quot; title=&quot;Blogger&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot; title=&quot;WordPress&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;.
For this reason, let’s start with a short introduction on Medium.
Started in 2012, it offers similar features like other platforms
where you could register to publish blog posts.
What makes Medium stands out is its unique user experience -
you can follow an user or an organisation, comment on specific section of a paragraph
and bookmark articles. Not to mention the clean design makes reading a pleasure
and there are a lot of good content available, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sundar_pichai/let-s-not-let-fear-defeat-our-values-af2e5ca92371&quot; title=&quot;Let’s Not Let Fear Defeat Our Values&quot;&gt;Let’s Not Let Fear Defeat Our Values - Sundar Pichai (CEO of Google Inc.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/300-awesome-free-things-e07b3cd5fd5b&quot; title=&quot;300 Awesome Free Things For Entrepreneur &amp;amp; Startups&quot;&gt;300 Awesome Free Things For Entrepreneur &amp;amp; Startups - Ali Messe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/life-learning/the-37-best-websites-to-learn-something-new-895e2cb0cad4&quot; title=&quot;The 37 Best Websites To Learn Something New&quot;&gt;The 37 Best Websites To Learn Something New - Kristyna Z.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;medium-is-blocked-in-malaysia&quot;&gt;Medium Is Blocked in Malaysia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since last week, Medium has been blocked in Malaysia
by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malaysian_Communications_and_Multimedia_Commission&quot; title=&quot;MCMC on Wikipedia&quot;&gt;MCMC (Malaysian Communications and Multimedia Commission)&lt;/a&gt;,
leaving Malaysian Medium users like myself wondering what to do. At this point, one might be curious why a blogging website is banned.
Before you guess piracy or pornography, the reason is apparently
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2016/01/28/malaysia-medium-block-explainer/&quot; title=&quot;Engadget: Why has Malaysia blocked Medium?&quot;&gt;Sarawak Report posted an article&lt;/a&gt;.
Yes, as ridiculous as it sounds, MCMC blocked the whole platform because of one user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-every-malaysian-should-be-concerned&quot;&gt;Why Every Malaysian Should Be Concerned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason is simple enough for Medium users -
you are now deprived of access to the entire website.
Yes, some tech-savvy persons might have found some ways to get around it
but that is far from a solution.
How can everyday regular internet users access it?
If you want to share posts targeted at Malaysians,
you can expect to reach little to none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, even if you are not a Medium user,
you should still be concerned about this level of internet censorship.
You certainly do not want a blanket ban like this to happen again
on an online service that you use.
It could be someone put up something deemed illegal
on Blogger, on Wordpress, on Thumblr, on Youtube, on Faceboook or on Twitter
caused those websites to be blocked in Malaysia
instead of having just the specific content censored.
Also, this is probably further damaging Malaysia’s reputation -
Medium is a very famous platform, what would foreign investors think?
It might not have an immediate, direct impact on everyone yet
but this is an unhealthy phenomenon no matter how you look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-do&quot;&gt;What Can You Do&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit that I do not know any good solution to this mess
but the very least everyone could do is
to raise your concerns on this matter
to your internet service provider (TM, Maxis, etc.) and MCMC.
Please, send them emails or call them,
let them know how the censorship has affected you,
ask for a solution from them, make your voice heard.
Do follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/UnblockMedium&quot; title=&quot;Unblock Medium&quot;&gt;Unblock Medium Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Be the change you wish to see in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2016/01/medium-is-blocked-in-malaysia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2016/01/medium-is-blocked-in-malaysia/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost in Malaysian Unity Run 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Runners gather at the starting point during Malaysian Unity Run 2015.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/12/2015-12-12-malaysian-unity-run-2015-starting.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a chilly morning, I arrived at the Putrajaya Wetlands Park around 7 A.M.
There were already a crowd, most were in the official light blue shirts of todays’s event - Malaysian Unity Run 2015. The colour was a good match for the clear sky. I had warm-up just like many other pumped up runners there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-peaceful-start&quot;&gt;A Peaceful Start&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the flag-off time drew nigh, people started to gather at the start point.
After the usual speeches and stretching, the 12 seconds countdown started on 12th December morning.
There was no air horn, the run started at 8 A.M.
The course was nice, it was one of the reasons I signed up
- greeneries and a good mixture of road and trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-amazing-race&quot;&gt;The Amazing Race&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere changed when many participants, myself included, were lost.
There was no marshals at junctions, runners were split into groups.
The group I was in missed the only water station and passed through a highway under the hot sun
while some others ended up running more than the intended 10 KM.
Fortunately, everyone managed to find their way back safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Malaysian Unity Run 2015 finisher medal.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/12/2015-12-12-malaysian-unity-run-2015-medal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fun-but-not-cool&quot;&gt;Fun But Not Cool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most runners were still quite cheered by the end of the event
and the organizer apologized for the incident.
While I liked the environment and the medal looks quite decent
plus there were some lucky draws alongside the prize giving ceremony,
it’s no excuse for the oversight, things could have ended up real bad.
I could still say I enjoyed the run only because no one was harmed.
After all, there are only so many runs where you could venture into unknown paths with other runners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2015/12/lost-in-malaysian-unity-run-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2015/12/lost-in-malaysian-unity-run-2015/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SCKLM 2015 Cancelled due to Haze</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dataran Merdeka covered in haze on SCKLM 2015 race day.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/10/2015-10-04-scklm2015-haze.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/11/penang-bridge-international-marathon-2014/&quot; title=&quot;Penang Bridge International Marathon 2014.&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned my intention to run a full, 42 KM marathon this year. So, signed up for one of the most respected marathon events in Malaysia - Standard Chartered KL Marathon (SCKLM), months of training, packs of power gel and carb loading; I believe many runners, like me, did not expect some slash-and-burn on the other side of the Strait of Malacca could ruin everything - the event has been cancelled on the day before the race day due to heavy haze. While disappointed, I understand that it must have been a difficult decision for the organiser seeing how everything has already been set up and ready. After all, health and safety are more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sportmanship-unfazed-by-haze&quot;&gt;Sportmanship Unfazed by Haze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, runners are going to the venue - Dataran Merdeka to collect entitlements without the run. I went there expecting it would be a gloomy one but hey, many are keeping their smiles, taking pictures wearing the finisher shirts while joking about how the finisher medals are the easiest one to obtain, I like the spirit. Good job to the cheerful volunteers too, some cheered for those coming to collect the entitlements as if they have just finished the run and some runners played along too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cheerful volunteers distributing entitlements to runners.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/10/2015-10-04-scklm2015-volunteers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this cancellation, my plan to run a full marathon this year is scrapped - it is already near the end of the year and registrations for other marathons in Malaysia have already been closed. Race again next year I guess, until then, more training.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2015/10/scklm-2015-cancelled-due-to-haze/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2015/10/scklm-2015-cancelled-due-to-haze/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Malaysia Fan Run 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 15 KM finisher medal.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/06/2015-06-02-longyc-teammalaysiafanrun-15km-finisher-medal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About half a year ago, I had my first 10 KM run at &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/team-malaysia-fan-run-2014/&quot; title=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014.&quot;&gt;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014&lt;/a&gt;.
This year, on 31st May, I went back for more – 15 KM.
Overall, the run was enjoyable although there were a few little disappointments with both the event and myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hot-sun--asphalt&quot;&gt;Hot Sun &amp;amp; Asphalt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag-off time for the 15 KM category was 7 A.M. -
it was very unlikely for most participants to make it within one hour but strong sun shines came after eight and there was not much trees to provide shade along the course at Putrajaya.
The view was nicer compared to last year’s Dataran Merdeka but hardly worth the heat.
Hopefully the organiser would consider to start at 6 A.M. or earlier for future events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2015 15 KM starting.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/06/2015-06-02-longyc-teammalaysiafanrun-15km-starting.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;less-impressive-medal&quot;&gt;Less Impressive Medal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the tiger strips Team Malaysia T-shirt that I liked still look as unique as ever,
the finisher medal feels a little over-designed compared to last year’s.
This can be very subjective but the ribbon bar definitely looks worse;
the three colours stripes has been replaced with logos of Telekom Malaysia and the hook is gone.
Last year’s medal is still one of my favourites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run Medals 2014 vs 2015.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/06/2015-06-02-longyc-teammalaysiafanrun-medals.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;could-not-run-much&quot;&gt;Could Not Run Much&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected myself to handle this one better after running regularly for almost a year
but the result turned out to be worse compared to last year’s 21 KM half marathon.
I ended up walking most of the time after the first 10 KM and my legs threatened to cramp.
Perhaps it was the heat or the uphills but in any case it means I need more trainings;
After all, I am going for a full marathon this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2015 at Putrajaya.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/06/2015-06-02-longyc-teammalaysiafanrun-fun.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, while last year’s run felt a bit better organized,
this year’s Team Malaysia Fan Run is still a very happening event and the theme song – “Gemuruh Suara” still rocks as ever.
I hope I will be able to join for the third time next year;
and as always, all the best to all Malaysian athletes, this time it is for the SEA Games 2015! Go Team Malaysia!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2015/06/team-malaysia-fan-run-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2015/06/team-malaysia-fan-run-2015/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Surprise Meeting Uncle Chuan</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;With Uncle Chuan from The Journey.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2015/05/2015-05-30-longyc-the-journey-uncle-chuan.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a crew shooting a movie at the park where I have my usual evening runs – I approached, I saw him, I shamelessly asked for a photo with Uncle Chuan (Frankie Lee) from The Journey which I watched twice in theaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must not have been easy for him – an English speaker who could not read Chinese to act as a Cantonese-speaking father that does not understand English well in the film; not to mention it was his first movie but the man in his 70s, against all odds, made it anyway and became a rising local actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case if you are not aware, The Journey (一路有你) is currently the highest grossing Malaysian film; it is a family movie about a series of heart-warming events of a conservative Chinese Malaysian father went through when his daughter brought back a British fiancé.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2015/05/surprise-meeting-uncle-chuan-from-the-journey/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2015/05/surprise-meeting-uncle-chuan-from-the-journey/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Penang Bridge International Marathon 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PBIM 2014 finisher medal.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/11/2014-11-16-longyc-pbim-medal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two months after my first 10 KM run, I have managed to finish a half marathon (21 KM) during Penang Bridge International Marathon 2014 held on 16th November at Sultan Abdul Halim Muadzam Shah Bridge (also known as Penang Second Bridge). I already have a new year resolution for 2015 – to complete a full 42 KM marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-experience&quot;&gt;The Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PBIM 2014 5 A.M. bridge view.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/11/2014-11-16-longyc-pbim-21km.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the running part, the first 10 KM felt quite okay, just a little bit out of breath. Things get tough after I stopped for a while near 13th KM, to continue running after a rest was painful so it was just walk-run afterwards. Took me close to 3 hours to finish even though there was very little elevations (around 30 metres, it was a bridge after all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the event as a whole, I read a lot of complaints about “human jam” at the finishing line and insufficient medals to give away because most full marathon and 10 KM runners completed their runs around the same time. I could only imagine how frustrating and demotivating it is to experience those problems right after finishing a long distance run. Lucky for me and probably most of the 21 KM runners that we did not had those issues. Regardless, the organizer needs to have better planning for events of this scale (over 60,000 participants this year) if they ever going to do this again next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wearing In-ear earphone when running.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/11/2014-11-16-longyc-ear-plug-stuck-marathon.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, I paused on my way to 13th KM, the reason being I got an ear bud stuck inside my right ear as the in-ear type earphone that I was wearing fell out. I said it during the run but I really need to say thanks again to the St. John volunteers who helped to get it out, if you are reading this, thank you so much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That must be one of the weirdest reasons to ask help from volunteers during a marathon and everyone laughed when I told them about this incident. I’m so going to get a pair of non in-ear type earphone for running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2014/11/penang-bridge-international-marathon-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2014/11/penang-bridge-international-marathon-2014/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014 finisher medal.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/09/2014-09-08-longyc-team-malaysia-fan-run-medal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is a mixture of tiredness and satisfaction because I have just completed my first ever 10 KM run this morning during Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014. Look at my shinning finisher medal. Granted, this is nowhere near a full-fledged 42 KM marathon but it is still a good start nonetheless and more importantly, I get to enjoy a fun event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fit-malaysia--minister-of-youth-and-sports&quot;&gt;Fit Malaysia &amp;amp; Minister of Youth and Sports&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;YB Khairy Jamaluddin - Minister of Youth and Sports at Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/09/2014-09-07-longyc-team-malaysia-fan-run-yb-kj.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event hold at Dataran Merdeka, Kuala Lumpur also served as the launching of the Fit Malaysia programme which aims to encourage active lifestyle among Malaysians. I would say the presence of Y.B. Khairy Jamaluddin – Minister of Youth and Sports at the event was a good catalyst, just look at the crowd when he went on stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-biggest-team-malaysia-fans&quot;&gt;The Biggest Team Malaysia Fans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;With Tok Mo at Team Malaysia Fan Run 2014.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2014/09/2014-09-07-longyc-team-malaysia-fan-run-tok-mo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also glad that I get to meet one of the biggest fans of Team Malaysia – Tok Mo from Famemas Malaysia Supporters Club. He was there with his signature Malaysian flag outfit and of course I would not miss the chance to take a photograph with him.
There were plenty of activities after the run but I did not stay because, well, I just wanted to go get some rest after the run. It was a great event and I will definitely join again if there is a chance. Last but not the least, all the best to all Malaysian athletes in the 17th Incheon Asian Games! Go Team Malaysia!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2014/09/team-malaysia-fan-run-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2014/09/team-malaysia-fan-run-2014/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DiGi Challenge for a Change</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DiGi Challenge For A Change hackathon.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2013/04/2013-04-08-digi-challenge-for-a-change-dgcfc-hackathon.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I attended HACK!@DGCFC – a 36-hour mobile apps hackathon organized by DiGi in conjunction with the ongoing DiGi Challenge For A Change (DGCFC) mobile apps development competition. The event was held right at the telecommunication company’s headquarters in Shah Alam, Selangor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-platform-hackathon&quot;&gt;Multi-platform Hackathon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I continue to write, let me just say it was a really nice event. One great thing about the hackathon was that it gathered software developers from different platforms because the competition was not limited to any mobile platform; apps can be built with Android, iOS, Blackberry, Windows Phone or HTML5, there was even a participant who developed on Nokia Asha. The demonstration session was a great showcase of current popular mobile platforms where you could see ideas being implemented on different systems and it was very exciting to see how the apps were made to utilize technology found on modern smartphones like Near Field Communication (NFC), accelerometer and gyro-sensor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DGCFC hackathon for all mobile platforms.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2013/04/2013-04-08-dgcfc-hackathon-all-platforms.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-thrown-in&quot;&gt;Everything Thrown In&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon was not all about coding, designing or free food (okay, maybe more or less about the free food), there were video games (Kinect and steering wheel included), basketballs, table tennis, futsal and the gym was open to everyone. Not to mention there was an amazing internet connection provided with speed up to 150Mbps which the network team challenged the participants to bring it down. That of course did not happen; perhaps everyone was too busy hacking their apps. There were talks by various speakers from different industries throughout the hackathon and I really enjoyed the great late-night chat with some of the cool guys there about recruitment, software developments, video games and everything in between. Oh, there was a brief detour of the headquarters too and it seems like a really nice place to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DiGi headquaters yard.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2013/04/2013-04-08-digi-headquaters-03.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-worth-the-weekend&quot;&gt;It’s Worth The Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a weekend well spent, the whole fun and eye-opening experience totally worth the sleepless night.
The winning teams of the mini challenges even walked away with Nokia Lumnia 920 and Blackberry Z10.
Below is a picture of the “hackathon finishers” taken from
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mydigi/status/320730498227908609&quot; title=&quot;Tweet by @mydigi.&quot;&gt;a Tweet by DiGi&lt;/a&gt;
(I guess I cheated a little because I joined on Saturday while the event started on Friday night).
It was a really cool event, the coolness was like
having a cup of free ice-cream 4 A.M. in the morning inside an air-conditioned room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DGCFC Hackathon finishers.&quot; src=&quot;/blog/2013/04/2013-04-07-dgcfc-finishing.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://longyc.com/2013/04/digi-challenge-for-a-change-mobile-apps-hackathon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://longyc.com/2013/04/digi-challenge-for-a-change-mobile-apps-hackathon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
